# 今天我拿點那個
Today, I'm taking the, you know,
# 來餵一下這個雞呦
to feed the, well, the chickens.
# 雞都跑出來啦
They've already run outside.
# 裡面那麼多穀子在裡面你都不進去 跑到外面來
Why don't you go inside? There're so many grains inside. Why are you running out?
# 你看 這個鵝
Look! The geese...
# 不敢來
They dare not come.
# 抓回來不適應
They're still not feeling at home.
# 可能較害怕
Perhaps they're a bit scared.
# 快點哦 等著你們下蛋哦
C'mon! I'm waiting for your eggs.
# 多吃點哦 多下兩個蛋
Eat more and lay some more eggs.
# 你看這些雞
Have a look at these chickens.
# 慢慢它就適應啦
They've started feeling at ease now.
# 現在可以吃一點飼料
Now they can start eating some fodder.
# 昨天一點都不吃
They didn't eat anything at all yesterday.
# 現在可以慢慢地吃一點
Now they've started eating a bit.
# 不過也是
But, you know,
# 慢慢習慣就好了
it's just a matter of time.
# 你看這個草
Have a look at the grass!
# 全部葉子都沒啦 就是這個鵝 這幾個鵝吃的
All leaves are gone. The geese, they were eaten by the geese.
# 壞的很 它們
The geese are really bad!
# 給它們吃它們又不吃
I did give them food. But they were not eating.
# 把它趕上山上去 那山上很多草
Let me drive them all onto the hill. There is plenty of grass.
# 啊 你提著小寶貝
Ah! You carry my little babe.
# 不要讓這些鴨子吃掉小寶貝了
Don't let these ducks eat my little babe.
# 哎呀 你跟我一起去嘛
Aya! Why don't you go with me?
# 大家好 我拿著一個狗
Hi everyone! I'm carrying a puppy,
# 在桶裡面
inside the bucket.
# 狗狗說話
Say something, puppy!
# 它不知道怎麼說話
He doesn't speak.
# 我們一起去看 那個白天鵝
We're gonna see the, the white swans.
# 不喜歡去那裡啊
They don't want to go there.
# 進去
Get inside!
# 這個沙樹 也沒人要的這個沙樹 (註︰不特色理會「沙樹」，亦不解釋了，反正不重要)
The tree, nobody is taking care of this tree.
# 幫它修 修很好看一點
Let me trim it, so that it looks better.
# 修得光溜溜的
It looks very bare now,
# 這樣好看
and is really nice.
# 太多葉子
They were too many leaves.
# 前面這個
The one in the front,
# 這種長刺的這個把它割掉
is some kind of spiky plants. I'm gonna cut them off.
# 把它摘掉
Let me get rid of them.
# 像這邊就很光啦
It seems that this side is already very bare.
# 看一下鴨子 在這上面
Have a look at the ducks. They're up there.
# 你看 它跟鴨匯合啦
Look! They've reunited with the ducks.
# 你看
Look!
# 鴨子也在這裡
The ducks are here,
# 鵝也在這裡
and the geese too.
# 這些鴨它們都在這裡
The ducks are all here.
# 多舒服啊
What a wonderful world!
# 有山泉水喝哦
They even have spring water.
# 這裡還有那個小魚 小蝦米在
Here are also some kind of small fish or small shrimps,
# 小蝦米之類的
small shrimps or whatever.
# 喝完了它們自己會回去的
They'll go back on their own when they have enough.
# 吃完它們又下去
They'll go down there after their meal.
# 這裡還有放魚的哦
Here are also some ponds for the fish.
# 這三個池塘裡面都放弓
I've put some, sort of like, some fish,
# 放了有那個魚下去
some snakehead fish,
# 放了一點蛇頭魚下去
into all these three ponds.
# 現在看都看下到
But I can't even see them now.
# 鴨子就不管它們 讓它們在這
I'm gonna leave the ducks alone. I'll let them,
# 自由自在地活著
enjoy their worriless life here.
# 等我們有空的時候
When we have more time,
# 就可以有鴨肉吃了
we can enjoy some duck meat.
# 哎呦
Ayo!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦 我們下次再見吧 拜拜
The video ends here. See you next time. Bye!
# 昨天我去兄弟家玩
I went to see my buddy yesterday.
# 你看 他主動拿了點這個西瓜苗給我
Look! He was so generous that he offered me some watermelon seedlings.
# 你看 拿了十幾棵給我哦
Look! He has given me a dozen of them.
# 可能是
Perhaps,
# 他 剛好碰到他 他也在種西瓜
he was, when we arrived, he was planting the watermelons.
# 摘了那麼多苗給我 我也自己種
Then he gave me so many seedlings. I'm gonna plant them here myself.
# 這裡種兩棵來
Let me plant a pair of them here.
# 你看 這個是西瓜苗
Look! This is a watermelon seedling.
# 你看 這樣很靚啦 這樣
Look! It's so beautiful, isn't it?
# 再澆點水下去就好啦
I only need to pour some water here.
# 嗯 你看 這裡還有一棵
Um, look! Here's another one.
# 種兩棵西瓜苗在這裡
So I plant two seedlings here.
# 到時候有西瓜吃啦
Then we'll have watermelons later.
# 還有 還有在上 上面那裡 那邊去種
The rest, I'll plant the rest up, up there, over there.
# 這裡也可以種一棵
I can plant one here.
# 這個都 都斷掉了一樣
The one seems, seems to be broken.
# 不知道能不能活
I wonder if it can survive.
# 裹點泥巴去
Let me wrap it with some mud.
# 活就活
Survive or not,
# 不活就 只能這樣啦
is its own destiny. I've already done my part.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 繼續往前面再種一點
Let's go on planting a bit more in the front.
# 種多一點吧 這裡種兩棵去
Why not plant a bit more? Let me plant two here,
# 它倆好有伴
so that they have a companion.
# 雙胞胎
They are twins.
# 這樣的話 長得就很靚這個
Then, when they grow up, they'll be really beautiful.
# 這樣種一棵算啦 不種那麼多
I just plant one here, not too many.
# 好啦 再往前面種
Alright! Let's move on and plant more.
# 終於搞定啦
Job done, finally.
# 這種 種西瓜真不容易
Plant, planting watermelons is really not an easy task.
# 這個太累啦 這樣
It's too tiring, really.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 我們回去啦
Let's go back.
# 下次 瓜熟的時候叫兄弟過來一起吃
Later, when the watermelons become ripe, we'll invite our buddy to come here and enjoy with us.